hoopla.net 2018-08-23

# Privacy Policy | Hoopla

**On May 25, 2018, Hoopla Software, Inc. (“Hoopla”) updated its Privacy Policy to reflect that Hoopla fully complies with the General Data Protection Regulation.**

The privacy of your personal information is very important to us. This statement outlines what personal information Hoopla collects about you and how we use it in the Hoopla application, widgets, products and services, our website located at www.hoopla.net (the “Site”), and our application located at app.hoopla.net (the “App”) (collectively, the “Service”). If you have any questions or concerns relating to privacy or security, please send an email to [privacy@hoopla.net](mailto:privacy@hoopla.net). 

Hoopla complies with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Frameworks as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield. Hoopla has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles with respect to such data. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and data subject rights under the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit [www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/). 

The United States Federal Trade Commission (FTC) is the enforcement authority with jurisdiction over this compliance with the Privacy Shield. 

Hoopla complies with the provisions of the Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament, known as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). For purposes of Article 14(2) of the GDPR, Hoopla relies on the following lawful basis for processing Personal Data: consent, compliance with law and legitimate interest. 

### **Information Collection**

To use the Service or to contact us for information about our services, you will have to provide the personal information needed to activate your account. By “personal information,” we mean data that is unique to an individual, such as your name, e-mail address, and company information, user IDs and passwords, online identifiers, device information, billing and transaction information, credit card or other financial information, contact preferences, and similar information. Hoopla collects information via email, through the Site, or other direct contact from you, and in the Service, that is voluntarily given to us. 

#### Tracking Technology

Tracking Technology: Cookies are pieces of data stored on your computer’s hard drive by a Web site. Cookies are an industry standard and used by most major web sites and online applications to improve their services. We tie personal information you provide to us to cookies. Hoopla uses cookies for user convenience. The cookie will tell our system certain information so you don’t have to fill in the same information each time you visit us. The cookie feature can be turned off on your browser. For more information on turning off the cookie feature, consult your browser “Help” section. If you choose to turn off cookies, you can still access some parts of the Service, but you won’t be able to access the App. 

We use our third party tracking-utility partners to gather certain information automatically and store it when you use the Service. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information to analyze trends, to administer the Service, to track users’ movements around the Service and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. 

#### IP Addresses

An Internet Protocol (IP) address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer by your Internet service provider whenever you access the Internet. This number may be the same each time you access the Internet or it may change. Like other Internet sites, Hoopla uses IP addresses to collect aggregate information about numbers of visitors and Site usage. Hoopla reserves the right to use IP addresses to identify individuals if (1) Hoopla is required to disclose such information by any applicable law or legal process (like a subpoena or court order); or (2) Hoopla is required to do so to protect the safety of the public or other users of the Service, to enforce the Terms of Use, or otherwise to protect our rights. 

#### Testimonials

We post customer testimonials/comments/reviews on our Site which may contain personally identifiable information. We do obtain the customer’s consent via email prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial. If you want your testimonial removed please contact us at [privacy@hoopla.net](mailto:privacy@hoopla.net). 

#### Blogs

Our Site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. 

#### Social Media Features and Widgets

Our Site includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button and widgets, such as the share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our Site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

### **How We Use Information**

If you provide personal information for a certain reason, we may use the personal information in connection with the reason for which it was provided. We use your personal information to provide you with access to your account, contact you or respond to questions about your account, resolve any problems you may have, send you notifications and reminders, invoicing, to better understand our users, and ask you for your feedback on how we can improve our Service. 

Unless you ask us not to, we may contact you via email in the future to tell you about specials, new products or services, or changes to this privacy policy. 

#### Data Retention

Hoopla will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. Hoopla will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

#### Security

We take precautions to protect your information and have implemented administrative, technical, and physical measures designed to protect your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, disclosure, use, alteration, or destruction. When you submit sensitive information via the Service, your information is protected both online and offline. Hoopla utilizes generally-accepted security measures (such as encryption) to protect against the misuse or unauthorized disclosure of any sensitive personal information you submit to us (such as log in information). However, like other Internet sites and web applications, we cannot guarantee that it is completely secure against attempts to evade security measures or intercept transmissions over the Internet. You are responsible for maintaining the security of your username and password for the Service. 

We also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information. 

### **Sharing**

We share aggregated demographic information with our partners and advertisers. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. 

Hoopla may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our Service. Transfers to these third parties are covered by the provisions in this policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our clients. We will never sell or share your personal information with third parties for marketing purposes or in ways other than as outlined in this privacy policy. 

We may also share your personal information with our subsidiaries and affiliates for purposes consistent with this privacy policy. As we develop our business, we might sell or buy businesses or assets. In the event of a corporate sale, merger, reorganization, dissolution or similar event, personal information may be part of the transferred assets. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. 

We use other third parties such as an email service provider to send out emails on our behalf. When you sign up for our services, we will share your personal information only as necessary for the third party to provide that service. 

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s) or blog, we will use your name and email address to send the related content to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter, blog updates, or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, or you can contact us at [privacy@hoopla.net](mailto:privacy@hoopla.net). 

#### Other Web Sites and Content

This privacy policy applies only to personal information collected by Hoopla through the Service. The Service may contain links to third-party sites or services, and once you leave the Service to visit another site, we have no control over your privacy or security issues even if you reached the other site by clicking on a link within the Service. We recommend you familiarize yourself with the policies of these other sites and services. Hoopla assumes no responsibility or liability for the availability or content of these outside sites, including any products, services or materials which may be available from such sites. Therefore, any concerns a user may have regarding any other site should be directed to the relevant site administrator or webmaster. 

Our marketing services partners, enable us to present you with information on our services based on your previous interaction with Hoopla. The techniques our partners employ do not automatically collect personal information such as your name, email address, postal address, or telephone number. In addition, we use Google, Inc. to collect data to track and examine the use of www.hoopla.net, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. 

Hoopla uses a third party credit card processing provider to manage credit card processing. This service provider is not permitted to store, retain, or use billing information except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on our behalf, and is subject to confidentiality obligations restricting the disclosure of information collected to other third parties. 

Under GDPR, Hoopla acts as a Data Processor vis a vis data provided to it through the Service by its Customers. Hoopla acts as a Data Controller with regard to data collected as part of its marketing activities. All transfers of data internally in the European Economic Area is done in accordance with Privacy Shield or Standard Contractual Clauses. 

Hoopla’s accountability for personal data that it receives in the United States under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party is described in the Privacy Shield Principles. In particular, Hoopla remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if third-party agents that it engages to process the personal data on its behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless Hoopla proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. 

Beyond the uses described in this privacy policy, Hoopla will not disclose to third parties any personal information gathered from you unless (a) you give us permission to share your personal information, (b) we are required to disclose such information by any applicable law or legal process (like a subpoena or court order) or (c) it is necessary to (i) protect and defend the rights or property of Hoopla, (ii) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public, or (iii) protect against legal liability. Please be aware that Hoopla may be required to disclose an individual’s personal information in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. If Hoopla intends on using any personal information in any manner that is not consistent with this privacy policy, you will be informed of such anticipated use prior to or at the time at which the personal information is collected. 

### **Your Choices, Access, and Control Over Information**

You may opt out of any future contacts from us at any time by contacting us via the email address or phone number given below. You may opt out of Google Analytics by visiting the Google Analytics opt-out page. If you choose not to provide any personal information, you can use the Service, but may not be able to use certain parts of the Service. 

Pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, EU and Swiss individuals have the right to obtain our confirmation of whether we maintain personal information relating to you in the United States. Upon request, we will provide you with access to the personal information that we hold about you. You may also correct, amend, or delete the personal information we hold about you. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data transferred to the United States under Privacy Shield, should direct their query to [privacy@hoopla.net](mailto:privacy@hoopla.net) or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. If requested to remove data, we will respond within the applicable legal timeframe. 

We will provide an individual opt-out or opt-in choice before we share your data with third parties other than our agents, or before we use it for a purpose other than which it was originally collected or subsequently authorized. To request to limit the use and disclosure of your personal information, please submit a written request to [privacy@hoopla.net](mailto:privacy@hoopla.net)

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

### **Children Under the Age of 18**

Our Service is not intended for children under 18 years of age. No one under age 18 may provide any information to or on the Websites, directly use the Service, or install the Hoopla Apps. We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from children under 18. If you are under 18, do not use or provide any information on our Websites or on or through any of its features, install the Hoopla Apps, or directly use the Service, including providing your name, address, telephone number, email address, or any screen name or user name you may use. If we learn we have collected or received Personal Data directly from a child under 18, we will delete that information. If you believe we might have any information from or about a child under 18, please contact us at [privacy@hoopla.net](mailto:privacy@hoopla.net). 

### **Dispute Resolution**

Any questions or concerns regarding the use or disclosure of personal information should be directed to Hoopla at the address given below. Hoopla will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of personal information in accordance with the principles contained in this policy. 

### **Privacy Complaints**

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Hoopla commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information transferred to the United States pursuant to Privacy Shield. European Union and Swiss individuals with Privacy Shield inquiries or complaints should first contact Hoopla at: 

Hoopla Software, Inc. Privacy Shield   
84 W. Santa Clara Street, Suite 460   
San Jose, CA 95113 

Or via email at [privacy@hoopla.net](mailto:privacy@hoopla.net). 

Hoopla has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit [www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/](http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/) for more information and to file a complaint. This service is provided free of charge to you. 

If your Privacy Shield complaint cannot be resolved through the above channels, under certain conditions, you may invoke binding arbitration for some residual claims not resolved by other redress mechanisms. See Privacy Shield Annex 1 at https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction [www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction)

### **Changes to this Policy**

This Policy may be amended from time to time, consistent with the requirements of the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles. All updates will be posted on this page. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. This privacy policy was last updated on the date indicated above. 

### **Other Terms and Conditions**

Your access to and use of this Site and the Service is subject to the [Hoopla Terms of Use](https://www.hoopla.net/terms-of-use).
